additional stage field in February by
news conference last he kept letters
procurement John Kiriakou I've active
hookah in Iraq for the CIA and yeah I
was a faculty those may be I canít
enhanced interrogation program for
innovative waterboarding Martella both
America and aid in Guantanamo Bay that
ability near Mayock and clear aku get a
dynamic for cloud motivated that's the
rain at the start of Martella in
Guantanamo Bay now can melt it in feud
that's all I keep on the Lincoln I can
move that um yeah about that same few
years of T I was living sack from Asajj
fell out Nicole attack and defend a
starter full of the color team select so
he thought the ability for that will
come active by many halfback lattice II
remember to see cities yeah it's
aromatic bleacher hinted at the bull
called me at Bosch itamarca a better
supplier they want to do list it
perfectly no danger bailiff with it at
all I said I will careful I see Bainer
this it takes or something every cake
another twenty funds to hold my laptop
up to death
solid and you federal petition to see
the sooner least to me to do with
cameras and my phone number to any fool
something like an al Bai flick and we've
been each on a canal dissection our
self-employed not a forced insurance
under she felt really be that Lorimer it
sort of Liza four different even if
anything for the media Corral the year
the sea half a mill thought for their
for specially booming music actors are
better to hang and the nostril develop
from for my Dana and my Christmas a
sniff heated on loss by attentive it's
like first off their background
throughout the ASL for that government
regime
I must not meet Antipater the best
conference he about her for all the
cameras could love something up sphere
builders in from from the dock from the
fee and sinister February that begins
met the father finest honesty Antelope
ready herself and Angus met the best
conference he he I found him on other
perhaps I was a historian expelled
associates or to see no we could and
about lost media canal detail help them
feel presumed he still be a super sphere
builders way hurry up yeah
[Music]
so you're going to be out here this is
I'm here for the five days yes so I'd
like to know if there's Dutch journalist
in there oh yeah at least somewhere
[Music]
sorry
three janitor Sarge
[Music]
[Applause]
what's my god it's a February 24th 2020
and my guest is junk karaoke
John is a CIA whistleblower or was oh
we're hang on let's just change my view
I'm recording on his own Vega was I
should say and is now a successful
author and a radio show host hello John
hello thanks for having me
yeah thanks for being back so I asked
you to comment on the expedition
hearings I shouldn't say trial a trial I
think my hearings over of Julian Assange
so let's dig into that what's your take
on what's happening here in London I'm
in London by the way so just you know
you're in London okay good well day one
this is a long process there it's a very
long process actually it's gonna stretch
into July by all accounts and there's
gonna be a break of at least a month in
the midst of this thing at the request
of the American prosecutors just because
they say they can't remain in London for
such a long stretch they're gonna have
to come back here and regroup I find
that to be very odd but I do think that
that the fact that it's scheduled for
such a long period of time is a good
thing for Julian because it's going to
give the defence
I think ample opportunity to get a lot
of facts into the record about the
American prison system that otherwise
would have been overlooked or ignored I
think that's a good thing but what would
be the top number one fact about the
American prison system that they meet in
them well it's what Neil's Mauser has
been saying the special the UN special
record tour for for torture that the US
practice of solitary confinement meets
the definition of torture at the United
Nations and and there's a precedent
there are actually several precedents in
British jurisprudence where prisoners
have been where the courts have refused
to extradite British prisoners to the
United States because they would be
subjected to solitary confinement so
fingers crossed I was I was not in the
courtroom I don't hold a press card so I
can't be journalists inside so I was
outside with the people protesting and
well there was some Brits there were
some people from London a Norwegian guy
Dennis got me from Holland and then the
French showed up yeah I heard it was
like 150 well we call them the yellow
vests and they they're the heroes of the
day days but they arrived in we're in
the morning and they didn't stop singing
until the court was recessed
banging defenses and everything and that
was weird heard also in in the
courtrooms now I just finished talking
to a member of European Parliament
market a Geiger vulva and she's here as
an observer and she said well there
weren't seats reserved for me as a
European Parliament member but I got in
line and I and and I was one of the
first people in I didn't know where to
go so I asked why was she here the guys
and he said well yeah a courtroom too so
she went there was empty sat down and
she stayed sitting there so the room
filled up as he was in there she wasn't
supposed to be the stories the stories
he told from the courtroom is that the
audio system was off so the microphones
weren't working so even people in the
room couldn't hear what the judge was
saying now Asajj was sitting behind a
plastic wall thingy so he had trouble
hearing his own courts this mess that I
just described is that common in United
States also no no it's funny to me that
they had him behind a plexiglass shield
the British do that for some reason not
all the time but sometimes that's
something that's just unheard of in the
United States and in the u.s. even if
the system even if the power were out
and I've never heard of anything like
that happening you're in such close
proximity to each other that you can
still hear what's going on the handful
of times that I've been in courtrooms
you didn't even really need a microphone
you're so close to one another that you
can hear everything but you know this I
have to say this doesn't surprise me at
all it sounds like more of a circus
sideshow than it does an actual legal
hearing yeah so so it's it's amateurism
if that's what you're saying that's what
it sounds like to me you think they
would have tested the sound system is
first on a case like this
so the impression that I got is and
here's a little lead-up to a more
serious question you have the French and
me and and the other guys outside
banging defenses
cheering cheering freedom of information
cheering derive for publishers to
publish right cheering lettuce on street
so that's this the one party in this and
on the other end you have the party that
wants him extradited
and in the middle there's the actual
courtroom with Asajj
now I would I would the word victim
might be out of context here but he's
sitting in the middle between those two
parties with his legal team up against
the American prosecutors but I'm a
Christian to you is who in United States
wants him extradited end of the line
really the only the only people the only
organization that is even talking about
extradition is the US Justice Department
certainly there's no movement among the
American populace demanding the head of
Julian Assange I said in an earlier
interview that at least 95 percent of
Americans have never heard of Julian
Assange they don't follow these issues
they don't pay any attention to the news
or to the case this is an act by the US
Department of Justice to try to
prosecute a journalist to try to
prosecute a publisher and so that's
where that's the driving force here it's
not the American public demanding that
someone pay for example for releasing
classified information the truth of the
matter here we go is that oh did I lose
you there you are for a second this the
truth of the matter is that that Julian
Assange blew the whistle on American war
crimes it is illegal in this country to
classify a crime if something is a crime
by definition it cannot be classified
and the American people have the right
to know what their what their government
is doing in their name Julian Assange
released that information that's a
public service it's not a crime so the
Justice Department is the Justice
Department and an extension of the
current administration in the White
House or is that disconnect it there
well in a way but in a way most of these
prosecutors are career prosecutors there
are the same people that were
prosecuting cases under Barack Obama and
under george w bush before him so i
don't think it's so much ideological as
it is institutional and and it's it's
the the professional prosecutors at the
justice department who are looking for
his scalp okay okay now what i
understand from the court documents is
that the extradition request
based solely on what's happened in the
Afghan locks Afghan war logs and
irregular war work so the stuff Chelsea
Manning leaked beckoned and it was
published in 2010 so why wasn't the
later stuff included there do you think
like 47 what was also through WikiLeaks
yeah my guess is that they're holding
that information in reserve in case they
they do get him here and he is somehow
acquitted of the the leaks in the Afghan
and Iraq war logs they have that in
reserve to charge him with new crimes
afterwards it sounds like it's personal
I'm going to ask you again who is the
host a person is there a person that has
a personal issue with Assange or is it
an institutional personal thing yeah I
think it's I think it's institutional I
think it's the the Justice Department's
National Security Division I think it's
the prosecutors in the Eastern District
of Virginia and certainly the judges in
the Eastern District of Virginia and
then you had this this completely
gung-ho Attorney General now former
attorney general in Jeff Sessions who
got them who got the wheels moving in
the first place
William bar William bar is not Jeff
Sessions his job is to protect the
president as he sees it and putting
Julian Assange in prison I think is
going to help with with the Republican
base okay we'll talk about Republican
base there's a as seen from this side of
the Atlantic there's a disconnect
between the DNC and the Trump group it
just is so you say 95 percent of
Americans may not have heard of the asan
story but is there a similar disconnect
between the other 5% and the general
population look like really apart yeah
there is there is because there are a
lot of Democrats who blame Julian
Assange personally for giving us Donald
Trump they believe that that his release
of the DNC
emails in the in the weeks before the
2016 election guaranteed Donald Trump's
victory and they just will not forgive
him for that
yeah but the previous question you're
also there was so it's the Justice
Department it's not the
not the DNC thing that that's involved
in this case right yes well the DNC
doesn't have the authority to do
something but my point really is that
that you know Democrats ought to be
Julian Assange's natural constituency
here it should be Democrats and
progressives who are in the streets
demanding that Julian be released and
it's not it's not in this case I mean
those of us who are true progressives
yes we're the ones that in the streets
we're the ones marching to the White
House and marching to the Justice
Department
but run-of-the-mill Democrats no because
they blame them for Donald Trump okay so
what's what what's going on in
Washington today what's there in a
demonstration yeah there's a
demonstration right now as we speak let
me actually look to see what time it is
it's two o'clock so I'm sorry it's
evening rose yes it's evening in London
two hours ago the demonstration began at
the White House it moved on to the Trump
International Hotel and from there it
went just another couple blocks down the
street to the Department of Justice to
the attorney general's office they're
gonna continue doing that every day this
week well just to keep up the pressure
and it's a variety of progressive groups
and transparency groups okay yeah which
I identify as Democrats then or is that
know talked about yeah no actually I
know all of the speakers and and no they
don't identify as Democrats they
identify as either independence or
greens because they believe like I do
that the Democratic Party is so similar
to and consistent with the Republican
Party that there's really not much of a
difference between the two people are
thinking that's going to might even
split even after these elections you say
I would not be surprised by that at all
and on the other side note you see
Clinton coming into the game again or no
it against her you know I I loathe
Hillary Clinton I think Hillary Clinton
was one of those dangerous political
figures of the last generation but the
rumor is that she might agree to be vice
president under Mike Bloomberg we just
have to keep our fingers crossed that we
don't trade one corrupt billionaire for
another corrupt billionaire and you know
I for one am I love Bernie Sanders I'm
going to proudly vote for Bernie Sanders
in two weeks and it looks like he has
enough momentum to put everybody else
away but that's not to say that the
Democratic National Committee won't
steal this thing from him at the
Democratic convention again exactly
as an aside looking back at 2016 Bernie
Sanders won the the West Virginia
primary and the Colorado caucus won
handily and didn't get a single delegate
in either one of those states Hillary
Clinton got all the delegates that's not
democracy that's best and we're afraid
of happening again exactly it does will
be my prediction so as seen from this
side of the Atlantic that's happen again
and that's gonna be the break up of
Democratic Party yeah and Trump's gonna
win anyway
another question I just told you I'm
gonna talk to ya well it's in the future
so I hope it's gonna pull through but
I'm about to talk to John McAfee yes all
right so he's the guy to the event it's
one of the first antivirus products now
he claims there is no such thing as
computer privacy or encryption
everything that works will have has been
compromised oh I believe he's taken a
different approach then at Snowden who
says well if you do properly encryption
works what's your take on that
well I'm not a computer expert but I've
been in touch with ed Snowden and Bill
Binney and Tom Drake and Kirk Wiebe and
guys who are computer experts and they
tell me that if the encryption is
sophisticated enough if the key is
sophisticated enough that it can work
the danger though is that it's
intercepted before you encrypt it so if
so if NSA for example is spying on you
or the FBI or CIA are spying on you and
they're able to target your computer as
you're typing your message before you
hit the encryption key then they've got
you yeah and so it's it's far less safe
and far less reliable than most people
realize I think so
only a week or two weeks ago by now in
the news was that a Swiss company crypto
AG right you've got that story oh yes so
yeah I'm asking a former CIA employee
but it was did you know about that back
in the day was this common no no no no
this was highly classified highly
compartmentalized you know I was in a
senior position of the CIA and I I had
no idea I gave an interview about this
last week to a Russian Network and it
was really one of the funniest
interviews I've ever given and I didn't
mean for it to be funny but this woman
was asking me very loaded questions like
is anybody going to be prosecuted for
this and I said no but I think several
people will probably win medals for it
this is a wildly successful operation
it's not viewed as a crime it's you it's
viewed as something heroic and patriotic
said she said but it's it's not honest
to do something like this and I said no
it's it's intelligence it's an
intelligence operation it's not supposed
to be honest it's not supposed to be
fair it's not supposed to make for a
level playing field this is something
that intelligence services do all around
the world yeah but still it is supposed
to be in the general public entry
or nose I mean says ooh yummy I mean why
else are we spending like it wrong why
else are we spending our tax money all
the time well this is in the public
interest it's in the US public interest
for the CIA to crack the codes of every
other country in the world very much in
the public interest yes I'm here
but the reason that I'm here is this
like like soul searching searching for
the soul in United Kingdom in London and
the activists here who shows up in the
journalists who show up politicians and
to see if Asajj has any chance at all or
not fair trial and then the microphones
don't work should they want and the
microphones don't work yeah so you know
one thing I'm worried about too is let's
say Julian let's say that the judge
denies the US government's request to
extradite Julian that's going to be seen
as a huge victory but then what happens
Julian is an Australian citizen he just
recently in the last year or so had his
Australian passport renewed so he has a
current passport if he's then expelled
from the United Kingdom and sent to
Australia the US will just ask the
Australians to extradite him it would be
so much better if he were allowed to
leave for Russia or if there were a
country that would be willing to brought
provide him with asylum because I don't
think that he would be safe if he wins
and he's expelled to Australia
how I don't know do United Kingdom legal
system but if you don't get extradited
you don't get expelled do you I mean
just read you sure you do because he's
not a British citizen he doesn't have a
right to remain in Britain no doesn't he
have two right to choose his own play
only she leaves I would hope so that's
really the big question I would hope so
so he's gonna say you know unless they
escort him to the airport and just put
him on the first plane to to Melbourne
Sydney France maybe I mean that would be
great
I heard he addressed asylum there yeah I
heard the same thing okay last question
that I have for you I prepared for you
you're aware you're familiar with a
software product called secure drop I
assume so I was not and I still don't
know it did the workings of it exactly
but on a higher level if you're a
whistleblower you have some stuff that
you want to expose to media you would
volunteer it to your drop and that
mechanism would land it to the media
without there being connection between
me and a material that I'm leaking right
that's security
yes okay yes and if you go to various
media outlets in United States you go to
the web sites you might find secure drop
on there as one of the means to to get
the information for them yes I got that
right and it was built among others
Assange was one of the people getting
that system working correct Aaron Swartz
was on there so these would be totally
independent people trying to get that
system to work okay my question is
there's not a product product as well
and that was global eeks that's also a
software product that was adopted maybe
among other parties but by a Dutch
organization pop leaks publics is using
the global leaks offer and does the same
thing and I just described have you
heard about publics before no this this
is the first time I've heard of it okay
well my question to you is if you find
the time and you know people I want to
know if I can how how I should weigh
publics as compared to secure drop Oh
most definitely bill Binney and and
Drake give you a detailed answer on that
I will connect it wonder better I'm
gonna connect to them excellent okay one
lasting forgot to write it oh yeah yeah
yeah ah before I hang up on this phone
in the Netherlands we have a law it's
called yeah in Dutch house/funk local
owner's home of whistleblowers now that
law sounds really great like some laws
tend to do so that's like a safe place
and built into law where whistle blows
can go so they don't have to leak to the
press how cool is that we don't need the
Fourth Estate because in the safe and
secure house of is Louis all things are
and you get even get some kind of
whistleblower certificates that you're a
real one so you're protected that right
I can form a Secret Service person in
the Netherlands is on the on their board
that kind of an organization so they're
about to evaluate that law and how it
frictions and well it doesn't really
function that well my question break if
you were to build an NGO and if you
would get a law in that would fund that
NGO through the tax money let's let's
let's just dream that that would be
reality someday who would be the people
deciding on who's on the board of such
NGO how would we get an abort and an
organization protecting whistleblowers
and their rights so that it's not
corrupted well actually such an
organization already exists
it's called blueprint for free speech
it's based in Australia and the board
members are mostly academics and some of
them are transparency and privacy
activists I've worked with them for
years and they've been able to write
draft legislation draft whistleblower
protection legislation and market it
around the world so they hired me in
2015 to help the Greek government write
a new whistleblower protection law we
wrote it in 2015 it was finally passed
into law in 2018 and then a version of
it was adopted by the European
Parliament for for implementation in the
European Union it's not perfect of
course because it had to go through so
many different layers of amendments and
in writing and rewriting and had to be
approved by all four different countries
but they've had success in places like
Canada and Zambia and Jamaica and
Ukraine pushing this whistleblower
protection legislation it's it's hard
work and it's a very long and drawn-out
process but it actually works in the end
in in most places that are serious about
that kind of legislation well the United
United baby I was going to say to your P
Union that they're not so so United as
they'd like to be but European Union has
a whistleblower directive that thing is
supposed to be passed into law in into
various Member States yes one of the
it's watered down right so that what's
really asking it also the restrictions
that that does not apply to is Brussels
itself so nice it's like a boat is the
United States but not for Washington
that's kind of a whistle blow it was and
that and that's how every piece of
legislation is here Congress is
automatically exempt from coverage like
for example OSHA the Occupational Safety
and Health Act Congress doesn't have to
observe any of it they exempt themselves
from coverage same thing all over but
okay you were involved with the thing
from Australia and it definitely kind of
research into that yeah to your
knowledge were they involved in any way
with the Dutch a law or evaluation is
taking place now um I don't know but I
can tell you that the that the founder
and director of blueprint for free
speech is dr. Salette Dreyfus who was
the co-founder of WikiLeaks with Julian
all definitely serious about
transparency okay you've given me
fantastic information job great to
target you again
my pleasure good to talk to you take
care of it bye-bye speaking of I yes we
Came we saw he died
[Music]
every nation in every region now has a
decision to make decisions you think I'm
joking
predators once you will never see it
coming
[Music]
knocks down the big game coming on over
here
[Music]